# Eric M. Contreras

## San Antonio, TX

Cell: (512) 981-8786 <u>www.linkedin.com/in/eric-contreras-ba32b018b</u> Email: michealecon@gmail.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

8 years of experience in the logistics industry, gaining valuable transferable skills in relationship building, strategic planning, and project management. Strong track record of quickly learning and adapting in new and complex situations. Eager to leverage a diverse range of talents in a new and engaging professional setting. Committed to lifelong learning and personal development.

### **SKILLS**

| <ul> <li>SQL</li> </ul>                         | <ul> <li>Report Analysis</li> </ul>            |
|---|--|
| <ul> <li>Excel</li> </ul>                       | <ul> <li>Pattern Recognition</li> </ul>        |
| Tableau   | <ul> <li>Problem Solving</li> </ul>            |
| <ul> <li>Data Visualization</li> </ul>          | • CRM  |
| CERTIFICATION                                   |  |
| Google Data Analytics Certificate               | SQL for Data Science, University of California |
| Data Analytics Certificate Course, Masterschool | Davis  |

#### **EDUCATION**

(Udacity)

**Bachelor of Business Administration in Finance -** The University of Texas at San Antonio 2022 to Present, Minor in Management Science

Associate of Arts - Northwest Vista Community College 2019-2021

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Dock Worker - H-E-B, San Antonio, TX

April 2019 - Present

Excel skill for Business, Macquarie University

- Collaborated with upper management along with facility operators to create safety program to integrate facility safety improvement, partner feedback reports, and performance awards
- Designed and implemented data visualization of safety performance within the facility to reflect statistics over previous years to current utilizing Microsoft Excel.
- Built out the data and reporting infrastructure of the safety training program leading to a rating of 100% success for the first time since 2014

### Transportation Specialist – United States Air Force, Fort Worth, TX

May 2014 – March 2022

- Conducted segregation and transfer of materials to specific holding areas while operating various dieselpowered vehicles along with additional powered materials
- Track inventory to provide records and reports for load planning coordination
- Process inbound/outbound shipments, verify content, while utilizing yard management for storage location

# Mac Expert - Volt, Austin, TX

May 2016 - March 2018

- Consulted customers about Apple technology through strategic problem-solving to isolate effective solutions
- Mentored and develop income experts in industry mission along with best practices for high performance
- Presented feedback for continued development of customer experience while implementing customer relationship management

### Project Management - Best Buy, Austin, TX

February 2014 – Oct. 2015

- Construct marketing display for varying clients within company industry and coordinated with load planning to maximize product/brand awareness
- Logged product inventory with key details for store reporting while simultaneously provided customer support to walk in customers
- Collaborated with clients to highlight critical features of tasked project in order to meet and exceed deadlines